Data Scientist

+94 77 25 65 240 ingallaba@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/osadainduwara

Summary

With more than 1.5 years of experience in Software Engineering and Business Intelligence, I've been involved in creating dashboard web application and building machine learning model to spot company issues. I am good in common sense coupled with knowledge in mathematics and AI. I'm eager to keep learning about the newest technologies. I'm actively pursuing a full-time **Data Scientist** position where I can apply my skills and knowledge to assist businesses and develop software solutions.



Work Experience

Dialog Axiata PLC

Former business inteligence developer (Internship)

May 2022 - April 2023

Accomplishments:

Used deep learning techniques. Learned XAI

Used AutoML techniques

Telecommunication Regulatory Commission
Sri Lanka

Former software developer (Internship)

Oct 2021 - April 2022

Accomplishments:
Developed a Django web application

Projects | Hands on experiences

Dashboard Web Application

- · Django backend with bootstrap frontend
- · MySQL database

Career guidance system powered by machine learning.

- · Django web application
- Regression model

Electricity usage forecasting of Signal towers

Energy forecasting for signal towers, leveraging both Artificial Neural Networks (ANN) and the FLAML automated
machine learning toolkit. I was able to generate more accurate energy forecasts for signal towers by utilizing the
aforementioned advanced techniques.

Apache Superset

 Apache Superset visualization of QGIS data exported through Postgres SQL. This involved designing, developing, and deploying interactive data visualizations utilizing Apache Superset, a business intelligence platform, to showcase geographic data.

Education

Wolverhampton University

Bachelor of Science Computer Science (Software Engineering) Second Class (2nd division)

Institute of Technology University of Moratuwa
National Diploma Technology
in Information Technology (NDT)

2019 - 2022

28th June 2023

Secondary Education

Dutugemunu College Buttala

GCE (A/L) 2017 Physical Science Stream, (Combined Mathematics Chemistry Physics - A C C)

2003 - 2017

Technical Skills and Tools

Skills

- Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Analytical Skills, Natural Language Processing (NLP), Data Preprocessing, Feature Engineering, Model Tuning and Hyperparameter Optimization, Cross-Validation, Anomaly Detection, DevOps and CI/CD
- Experience in using AI tools like ChatGPT and other alternatives, if required

Languages, Libraries and Frameworks

 Python, HTML, CSS, scikit-learn, NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Django, FLAML, H20, XGBoost, React

Technologies

· PostgreSQL, AWS, Google Cloud, Docker, GIT, Jira, RESTful APIs, Kubernetes

Software Tools

· Apache Spark, Google Colab, Qgis, Apache Superset, Visual Studio Code, Jupyter Notebook

Soft Skills

Analytical Thinking, Problem-Solving, Curiosity and Learning Agility, Collaboration and Teamwork, Open-mindedness.

Referee

DR.MRS K Galappaththi

Head of the division of IT Institute of Technology University, of Moratuwa

Phone: 0714434530

Email: kgalappaththi@yahoo.com